When asked to describe Fallout 3, Bethesda said it was a game where you sneak into strangers houses and steal stuff you can't actually use.
I wanted to know if there was more to it than that and no, no there is not.
Last time I said I was gonna do a recap of Dark Souls, but then a stranger wrote this passionate comment
And you know what they say Fallout 3 is the Dark Souls of post-apocalyptic First-Person Shooters.
In the Fallout games the planet has been destroyed by a nuclear war. Why?
I don't know actually, I didn't read up on the backstory or anything like that
but I'm blaming Norway. The game starts with you being born, then you get to name your
character. You guys know I'm not a very creative person
so I just named him 'Fallout 3'. You get to decide what your character looks like. Obviously Bethesda is famous for their
open and massive worlds, but they're also famous for how impossible
it is to create a good-looking character. After that you encounter something else Bethesda puts in every single game they make.
Just gonna change this, then we are ready to go. You kill your mother, now time is moving faster.
You are now a baby in a massive underground Vault and your dad....
And your Liam Neeson tells you about your mother 'Look son,
this was your mother's favorite passage, and by the way, it's also foreshadowing.' Time moves forward a bit more and it's your birthday!
You just turned 10. It's really slow and boring. This kid is a bit annoying. then he dies of 'natural causes'
After about 70 minutes spent in this place, Liam Neeson tells you to go to the basement.
You get a machine gun and then time moves faster and stuff?
You know what let's skip a bunch of stuff, because everyone has played this part at least 17 times.
You meet the Tunnel Snakes and everyone you meet after these fellows are complete losers.
You get points in Unarmed that you have to change
Albanian Mafia kills this guy and Liam Neeson leaves the vault seeking revenge
And then you follow him. A bunch of other shit also happens, but that's not really important
Congratulations, now the game actually starts
You look around and realize that having the world destroyed by nukes is not really as fun as it sounds
Every nice plant is dead
And you are surrounded by danger. For example, Cannon fodder, or the raiders as they like to be called,
They die when you look at them funny the death claw I keep hearing [people] saying these guys are hard
I don't get it. All you have to do is open the developer console and write kill The Radscorpions
They kill you but they also make you feel insecure when they show off their radical
BMx tricks you make your way to town called Megaton only it's a town built around the nuke and there are actually people in the
Town that worships the nuke you might be laughing at them, but let's be honest
God caused a mass extinction because humanity was being shitty these fellows didn't even need a reason
[I] think you're under estimating nuclear weapons [you] go to a bar to [ask] [about] your missing dad
Yes, I miss your father, but information costs money, but don't worry
This is a [bethesda] game, and you can do me a favor who you can pay me
100 caps
Just realized that's not a lot of money, shit. In the bar there's also this guy that wants you to detonate the nuke
Obviously, I didn't do [that] because I'm not a cunt, but I bet you did, you dickhead. You are supposed to go to this place
But this girl wants you to deliver a letter so I'm just gonna do that first
Did I forget- oh fu- the main quest your father apparently went to the Galaxy news radio station?
But it's impossible to find
Therefore you're going to spend a lot of time in the city, and that made me wonder
Where are we because we don't know bethesda has never officially declared where fallout 3 takes place?
This brings me to a completely new segment called game theorizing
Hi, Interwebs welcome to game
Theorizing, so where does fallout 3 take place? We know it's in the country United States, and we keep hearing
Washington now you might be saying hey, [I] know Washington
Isn't [that] where that masterpiece Cory In The House takes place? You would be right,
But here's the thing: believe it or not the house is actually real
It's called the white house, and it's Washington's most popular tourist attraction. So [we] should be able to find it
Huh according to Google maps the white house should be north of the Washington monument, [but] if we actually go north of Washington monuments
There's nothing here
So we have no way of knowing if this actually is Washington, the City and here's where things gets weird
[you] see the yanks have these self-governing regions called [staties], and there's one called you guessed it
Washington it's a bit confusing, but could this be the place well, we don't know there's also a statie called
Virginia and one called West Virginia you see, that's that's ridiculous
That's just silly
What are we talking about? My point is Americans should stick to
researching and inventing stuff and just stay away from naming large chunks of land, but hey,
That's just a theorizing, a GAME
Theorizing! join us next week when we'll talk about how five nights at [Freddys] has a better story than anything written by tolstoy
The biggest problem with Nuclear holocaust is that there is no private place to pee you get the radio station now
You have to defend it from a bunch of attacking Super Mutants can like normal mutants, but Super oh
What a surprise liam neeson is not here. He's at the boat city. [oh], what a surprise
Ra's Al Ghul is not here. He thought the Jefferson memorial
Jefferson Memorial here's the problem with not knowing the Backstory or the Lore
I have no idea this yet person guy is in the building you find these recordings left by your dad
Look, I'm going to Vault 112 to look for Stanislaus Browns research. I have marked on the map
I have also marked the best must-sees in DC check out the doll Museum
Criminally underrated you get to the vault and you find these people locked into these
Virtual reality pods you go into one of the pods and you meet the german [scientist] behind it all
Told Howard speaking. hi, It's me sir calling from the studio
We're about to do stanislaw Brown, just a question why does he have a German accent?
He's an evil scientist, not that many nationalities to choose from
Yeah, I get that
But he's been in the pod for what two hundred years only interacting with Americans surely he would have lost his accent by now
That makes sense I guess you know what change the accent
But after you do that don't forget to sign up for unemployment benefits
Stanislav Brown tells you Moscow Moscow [VFD] glaser and Eve and Austin is to show, nesland
[ohohohohoh], hey you don't though you go into this house and press a bunch of stuff then you activate the Chinese invasion mode
take Note software developers
Imagine editing of 20,000 word document and
Accidentally enabling Chinese invasion mode that would be hilarious
You get out and your father tells you that he knows a perfect way of purifying water because apparently
Nuclear Waste makes water taste bad
[so] he and a bunch of scientists gather in front of the Jefferson memorial
And you have to fix a bunch of stuff before they can go in
It's incredibly boring, and I'm just going to do this one two thing before it. [oh]
Shit the main quest so you walk [around] the action memorial and fix a bunch of stuff then these guys show up the armed clay
It's a sort of resurrection of the United States government, but a bit more popular
Hi, there. We heard about your project
And we the anche would like to help we have lots of resources for example [scientist] and tools
And no get out is a private project, and you can all go eat a dick [okay]?
[that's] not exactly how I expect you to go, but you know what okay?
We're gonna respect your privacy and we're going to leav- A Captain goes down with his ship!
Liam Explodes the thing and the entire room gets filled with deadly radiation
You have to escort the other scientists [to] place known as the citadel where the brotherhood of steel is one of the scientists tells you?
To [purify] water we need some called a geek it's it's a box full of geckos
Don't even ask but it's involved and you have to go search for it
So you go towards the vault and in front of it. There's a city where only children live
Hey Mungo, this is an A and B [hi Mungo] conversation so C your way out
And in front of it
There's a radioactive crater to get the get you have to go through this room filled with deadly radiation
[if] you find yourself in this situation in real life, just be
confident
Remember that the radiation is just as scared of you as you are of it
You retrieve the cake and you're about [to] leave then you get kidnapped. It's the Albanian mob.
Oh good you're awake. We thought you were a goner.
We saved your life and removed the radiation then we restored your- got to follow dad
So you go to the brothers of Steel and they're like "Fuck the Enclave"
We have a giant robot
So you and a giant robot take back lipson or you'll give me the colonel again the last duel
You versus the man
Responsible for your father's death, and he dies after two seconds don't know what I expected
She goes in and sacrificed herself because of all the radiation and then there's his slide show and so it [hums]. That's that's it
[that's] the actual ending
No, of course not don't be daft [you] [see] [as] you thought they create this massive blockbuster game and had that as the ending
No
You have to finish every single quest when you're done with that you can return to the Vault and everything is great
Your dad's there also
He beats up death and came [back] to life then the alarm goes off
The Enclave is attacking
they have Gathered an army outside the vault all you have to have to do is to walk out and just turn around and
They will please
Because it doesn't matter if you're a doctor an engineer a YouTube gamer or the United States government
Nobody messes with a tunnel snake (Tunnel Snakes Rule!), then you get a real ending
But I won't spoil it here and that is the Kilian experience. Did you like the video anyway? It's neat time
I make a sequel to my most liked video. It's Assassin's Creed 2 time yay
This is probably where you want me to talk [about] a bowl of mixed [vegetables], but that's not gonna happen